<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-05-27T19:14:45-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/feed.xml</id><title type="html">The Coolest blog ever</title><subtitle>This is my blog, I come here to periodically track progress, be sad, remind myself how to use html, or just talk about stuff I do that I think is cool.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Denver Colorado</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/personal/2022/05/21/Denver,-CO.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Denver Colorado" /><published>2022-05-21T12:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-05-21T12:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/personal/2022/05/21/Denver,%20CO</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/personal/2022/05/21/Denver,-CO.html">&lt;p&gt;I apologize in advance, I have a lot to say in this one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a mini road trip, it was pretty swag. I stayed in my favorite national park. The Great Sand Dunes National Park for two days.
 The drive here was kinda surreal, I passed through the Rockies where it snows year round. But it was still so odd to see one part of this state covered in snow, and then not even an hour away, just the most massive desert.  I’ve only ever been here once before, this is my second visit, but its the first time I got to sandboard. It was kinda hard, like really difficult to balance, and you need to use a ton of wax. But once you get used to it, and get going on some slopes, its so fun. Its so much harder than skateboarding which is hard to imagine. But I think that I came at a pretty good time, it’s really windy this weekend (15 mph) which is sick for sandboarding. But its also really cold (&amp;lt;40° at night) so that kinda sucks but what are you gonna do. There are also frequent bear attacks in this area, which is a little scary, but if it was that bad they wouldn’t let people camp here. But yeah here for two days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My job is pretty fucking cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel very odd about conventional social media. I still use it everyday. But I don’t really like it. It makes it so easy to compare yourself to other people, and it leaves so much out. Its a virtual representation of yourself that you get to define, and I don’t see that it is always accurate. The ways that social media let us express ourselves are limited, and up to the designer. They make a limited amount text, images, or a time limit on videos be the&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People only reach out when they see something from you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least a little bit of this stems from taking Latin in high school. Incase you were blissfully unaware, Latin is a very complicated language. Basically you end up translating a large paragraph as a single sentence with multiple clauses. There is usually no punctuation, which means you need to use the 5/6 different forms of each word to determine its relation and place in the sentence. If it sounds complicated that’s because it is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But yeah Denver, CO is where i’m posted up for this summer. Very happy about it&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">I apologize in advance, I have a lot to say in this one.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Back Home</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/personal/2022/05/14/Back-Home.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Back Home" /><published>2022-05-14T17:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-05-14T17:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/personal/2022/05/14/Back%20Home</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/personal/2022/05/14/Back-Home.html">&lt;p&gt;I did it. I made it through another semester at HDX! Not like it is usually challenging but this previous one was particularly bad for me. I kinda sorta did some cool stuff for a final project, working with facial detection algorithms and pizza. It didn’t go the exact way I planned and if you know me, procrastinating is my favorite hobby. But I feel like I missed a shot to do something really fun. If you wanna look at it, its [here] (https://github.com/KadenFranklin/pizza_pasta). Maybe one day I’ll finish it completely far past the deadline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But yeah I am back home for a week and a half. I finally got around to fixing the css styling of this blog, it looks pretty swag if I do say so myself. I finally figured out how to do stuff under the hood of these jekyll.md files, so I am actually enjoying this blogging thing. The Arboretum is being diligently worked on by Dr. Goadrich and I am excited about the future for a change. I am going to Colorado for the summer. I am doing trail maintenance with MHYC in Denver. I may or may not be camping an unhealthy amount and or living out of my car. But I’m not really as scared as I think I should be. I feel like if anything I really want to do it. It is such a change from what is normally going on in my life I feel like it will be so good for me. I get to live in the mountains, high elevations means less dense air so I will come back home with the endurance of a greek god. I know I am going to get bored, so I got the classic gameboy color with the old cartridges, you already know. I also got a switch, but other than those two things and work, I think I will just mostly rock climb. There are so many gyms in denver, I am going to get so good at reading routes, I want to see just how good I can get at rock climbing. But yeah, very exciting I might post here more might not who knows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m gonna try to figure out how to upload a video on here, and maybe fill a webpage with images of variable size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But don’t hold me to that.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">I did it. I made it through another semester at HDX! Not like it is usually challenging but this previous one was particularly bad for me. I kinda sorta did some cool stuff for a final project, working with facial detection algorithms and pizza. It didn’t go the exact way I planned and if you know me, procrastinating is my favorite hobby. But I feel like I missed a shot to do something really fun. If you wanna look at it, its [here] (https://github.com/KadenFranklin/pizza_pasta). Maybe one day I’ll finish it completely far past the deadline.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">An iteration of maps</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/hendrix/arboretum/2022/03/19/An-iteration-of-maps.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An iteration of maps" /><published>2022-03-19T02:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2022-03-19T02:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/hendrix/arboretum/2022/03/19/An%20iteration%20of%20maps</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/hendrix/arboretum/2022/03/19/An-iteration-of-maps.html">&lt;p&gt;The Hendrix Arboretum is a project I have been working on for a while. It was a class project for CSCI 340, but my group ran into a bunch of problems. So I have kind of been working on it for way longer than I need to but that’s alright cause its hard for me to give up on things. I had versions of this project saved through its incremental development over the past months, and I thought it would be cool to leave a record of that here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kadenfranklin.github.io/actually-a-map/Oldest/The%20Hendrix%20College%20Campus%20Arboretum%20_%20Hendrix%20College&quot;&gt;Oldest&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There already existed a webpage for the Hendrix Arboretum but it was not interactive, or anything it just kinda explained what it was. I copied saved a version of the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hendrix.edu/biology/biology.aspx?id=3645&quot;&gt;webpage&lt;/a&gt;, and started looking at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/bingmaps/v8-web-control/map-control-api/&quot;&gt;bing maps api&lt;/a&gt; to figure out how the heck it worked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kadenfranklin.github.io/actually-a-map/Old/The%20Hendrix%20College%20Campus%20Arboretum%20_%20Hendrix%20College&quot;&gt;Old&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On this the only real development was that I made it access the correct css files. Definitely took me way too long to figure this on out. For future reference, the difference between this and the first is ‘./’ preceding some files instead ‘..’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kadenfranklin.github.io/actually-a-map/Middle/The%20Hendrix%20College%20Campus%20Arboretum%20_%20Hendrix%20College&quot;&gt;Middle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I changed the css a little bit. Added a border around the map, added the search bar and made trees searchable by number I think. Also made buttons for specialty categories, but the buttons did not actually do anything in this version. There are trees on this map, but they are randomly generated, you can click them and see the infoboxes I made, their links and pictures do not work without the rest of the project though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://kadenfranklin.github.io/actually-a-map/New/The%20Hendrix%20College%20Campus%20Arboretum%20_%20Hendrix%20College&quot;&gt;New&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the first version of the map that was actually linked to the database. That is why you see the for each item in Model.specialties. It also read tree coordinates from the database as well, but for the last HTML file I just left it reading 5 random locations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then the Arboretum has been worked on by Dr. Goadrich and DiscoTray studios. I helped with some miscellaneous tasks along its development, but it turned out great. &lt;a href=&quot;https://hendrix-arboretum.azurewebsites.net/&quot;&gt;You can see it here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Hendrix" /><category term="Arboretum" /><summary type="html">The Hendrix Arboretum is a project I have been working on for a while. It was a class project for CSCI 340, but my group ran into a bunch of problems. So I have kind of been working on it for way longer than I need to but that’s alright cause its hard for me to give up on things. I had versions of this project saved through its incremental development over the past months, and I thought it would be cool to leave a record of that here.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A list of things to be excited for</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/personal/2022/03/10/Things-to-be-excited-for.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A list of things to be excited for" /><published>2022-03-10T01:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2022-03-10T01:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/personal/2022/03/10/Things%20to%20be%20excited%20for</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/personal/2022/03/10/Things-to-be-excited-for.html">&lt;p&gt;Since my last post was literally the most embarrassing thing ever, here is something more fun n cheery.
A List of things to be excited for (in no particular order):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Outdoor rock-climbing trip&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Spring break road trip&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Learning a new programming language called jack&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Finishing arboretum website&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Meditations&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Writing songs with the boys&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Seeing peter (dog)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Watching adventure time again&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Making a &lt;a href=&quot;https://sonic-pi.net/&quot;&gt;Sonic Pi&lt;/a&gt; type beat&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Internship&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Fixing the css of this dang blog&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Learning to play bass&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Personal" /><summary type="html">Since my last post was literally the most embarrassing thing ever, here is something more fun n cheery. A List of things to be excited for (in no particular order):</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Service to the world reflection</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/school/2021/12/08/SW-Odyessey_Reflection.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Service to the world reflection" /><published>2021-12-08T01:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-12-08T01:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/school/2021/12/08/SW-Odyessey_Reflection</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/school/2021/12/08/SW-Odyessey_Reflection.html">&lt;p&gt;Throughout the course of this semester I have been able to see what it is like to work on a team and build a website for a client. The ability to work with a community partner mimics the sort of relationship you could have with a potential boss in the future. The opportunity to bring your clients ideas to life through the website is spectacular and provides a sense of fulfillment. The real takeaway is that every group in this class is building something that effectively helps the community in some way, whether that be educational through a nonprofit, etc. It is a well known fact that programmers stand to profit a lot in this day and age. This class has given me a chance to see that it is important to give back to ones own community because we stand to gain so much.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="school" /><summary type="html">Throughout the course of this semester I have been able to see what it is like to work on a team and build a website for a client. The ability to work with a community partner mimics the sort of relationship you could have with a potential boss in the future. The opportunity to bring your clients ideas to life through the website is spectacular and provides a sense of fulfillment. The real takeaway is that every group in this class is building something that effectively helps the community in some way, whether that be educational through a nonprofit, etc. It is a well known fact that programmers stand to profit a lot in this day and age. This class has given me a chance to see that it is important to give back to ones own community because we stand to gain so much.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Entity Framework lab lab 8</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/school/2021/12/08/Entity_Framework.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Entity Framework lab lab 8" /><published>2021-12-08T01:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-12-08T01:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/school/2021/12/08/Entity_Framework</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/school/2021/12/08/Entity_Framework.html">&lt;p&gt;Overall the tutorial was not that complicated it was simply long. It did not help that I waited so long to complete it… It had a lot of parts but most of it was copy paste. There were some parts that were confusing in the beginning. Dealing with multiple tables and implementing age for students were confusing in particular. The amount of things that need to be changed with multiple tables makes all the work feel tedious. But after completing this lab I feel confident in the database that we have for the arboretum website.
Here is the link to the complete projects repository:&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/DaltonCompSci/csci340lab8&quot;&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The instructions for the lab can be found here. &lt;a href=&quot;https://hendrix-cs.github.io/csci340/labs/ef.html&quot;&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="school" /><summary type="html">Overall the tutorial was not that complicated it was simply long. It did not help that I waited so long to complete it… It had a lot of parts but most of it was copy paste. There were some parts that were confusing in the beginning. Dealing with multiple tables and implementing age for students were confusing in particular. The amount of things that need to be changed with multiple tables makes all the work feel tedious. But after completing this lab I feel confident in the database that we have for the arboretum website. Here is the link to the complete projects repository:HERE</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Azure Remote Hosting lab 9</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/school/2021/12/08/Azure_Remote_Hosting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Azure Remote Hosting lab 9" /><published>2021-12-08T01:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-12-08T01:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/school/2021/12/08/Azure_Remote_Hosting</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/school/2021/12/08/Azure_Remote_Hosting.html">&lt;p&gt;For the most part I did not have a large stake in lab 9. I had fallen behind in te labs so by the time I was able to work on it the lab was done. I did end up having a third party host the images for our website. I went through many stressful processes trying to get something to work proper and ended up fine in the end. The finished repository for this lab can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/qsebring3930/csci340lab9&quot;&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The link to this labs instructions can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://hendrix-cs.github.io/csci340/labs/azureremote.html&quot;&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="school" /><summary type="html">For the most part I did not have a large stake in lab 9. I had fallen behind in te labs so by the time I was able to work on it the lab was done. I did end up having a third party host the images for our website. I went through many stressful processes trying to get something to work proper and ended up fine in the end. The finished repository for this lab can be found HERE</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reflection Post!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/school/2021/09/17/Reflection-Post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reflection Post!" /><published>2021-09-17T04:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-09-17T04:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/school/2021/09/17/Reflection%20Post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/school/2021/09/17/Reflection-Post.html">&lt;p&gt;This lab did not take me as long as the previous one. I feel like both have given me a good grasp of how to work with a system like jekyll and websites that are set up in this manner. The only thing that took some considerable effort was getting other .md files to appear in the nav bar. (I accidentally edited index.md and that set me back for a minute.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not believe there is much else to say about this lab. Thus I will leave you with some links that helped me complete this and some pictures of my dog peter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://stackoverflow.com/questions/41604263/how-do-i-display-local-image-in-markdown&quot;&gt;Link 1!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://anvilproject.org/guides/content/creating-links&quot;&gt;Link 2!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kadenfranklin.github.io/blog/assets/peter_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A picture of Peter!!!1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ah he’s so cute!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://kadenfranklin.github.io/blog/assets/peter_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;A picture of Peter!!!&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="school" /><summary type="html">This lab did not take me as long as the previous one. I feel like both have given me a good grasp of how to work with a system like jekyll and websites that are set up in this manner. The only thing that took some considerable effort was getting other .md files to appear in the nav bar. (I accidentally edited index.md and that set me back for a minute.)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Introduction Post!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/school/2021/09/13/Introduction-Post.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introduction Post!" /><published>2021-09-13T00:19:00-06:00</published><updated>2021-09-13T00:19:00-06:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/school/2021/09/13/Introduction%20Post</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/school/2021/09/13/Introduction-Post.html">&lt;p&gt;Here we go the first official post on my blog. My experience in setting up this blog was fairly easy. I think it is so easy, practically anyone could do it given the right instructions and guidance. All it really took was installing ruby and a couple things through the command prompt. I did accidentally skip a step. This left me without some of the critical sections of this blog that make it function as a real website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After some time and assistance from my professor, I fixed my mistake and got this blog to its current state. If you plan on following in my footsteps I recommend that you:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*Read directions a few times over
*Double check to make sure your commands are executed
*Do A little bit of research about what you are installing
*Think Creatively, it can only get better from here&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you are so enthusiastic about making your first blog you cannot control yourself. You may follow the directions &lt;a href=&quot;https://hendrix-cs.github.io/csci340/labs/jekyllmods.html&quot;&gt;HERE&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="school" /><summary type="html">Here we go the first official post on my blog. My experience in setting up this blog was fairly easy. I think it is so easy, practically anyone could do it given the right instructions and guidance. All it really took was installing ruby and a couple things through the command prompt. I did accidentally skip a step. This left me without some of the critical sections of this blog that make it function as a real website.</summary></entry></feed>